# **LANDON MORGAN**

PHONE: 615-307-0005

EMAIL: MORGANLANDON@GMAIL.COM
WEBSITE: IANDONMORGAN.GITHUB.IO
GITHUB: GITHUB.COM/IANDONMORGAN/
LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN.COM/IN/LANDOLAKE/

# **ABOUT ME**

My professional background is primarily in video production and live tv entertainment. Since the mid-1990's, I proactively sought codecentered side hustles. My first experiences with programming languages were seeing C++ and coding in HTML when I was 15. The site my friend Luke and I created was featured in USA Today.

I created nashvillePA.com in 2007 to get my friends and production assistants in Nashville their next gig. In 2010 I was commissioned to build holyvintage.com, a retail site managing an inventory of vintage t-shirts with only my knowledge of HTML. I have a technical mindset and thrive in roles where I wear multiple hats.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Software Developer**

Simple Modern | July 2020 - Present

- Technical support and development for website and internal web application.
- Technologies and languages used include git, Github, Terminal, VS Code, IntelliJ, Clojure, ClojureScript, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Shopify Liquid, Datomic, AWS.
- Managed internship curriculum for Technology Department

# Manager, Video Content Production Sony Music Entertainment | Aug 2017 - Dec 2019

Sony Music Entertainment | Aug 2017 - Dec 2019

- Designed and maintained intake form to process the workflow of project requests from other departments
- Liaised with all departments for video content needs
- Researched and targeted top creatives in Nashville and commissioned video work to independent contractors, sustaining a 20% network growth (active freelancers)
- Found, recommended, trained, and mentored the person who later applied for and was promoted to manager following my departure
- Communicated status and updates to artists and management teams through regularly scheduled meetings, or during projects

### **Talent Supervisor (Live TV Events)**

#### One Foot Productions | Aug 2014 - Aug 2017

- Led team of liaisons to manage the logistics related to participating and performing artists, and the artists' band, crew, management and label teams for large scale live tv events
- Supervised core team of approximately 30 people, with up-to an additional 100-150 talent escorts for show day
- Worked with project manager to communicate logistics team needs to the software developers
- Annual events worked include Rock and Roll Hall of Fame Induction Ceremony, Nickelodeon HALO Awards, BET Experience, iHeart Radio Music Awards, and more

#### **Producer (Video Content)**

#### AOL StudioNow | Jan 2011 - Mar 2014

- Personally recruited and onboarded hundreds of freelance video professionals into the AOL StudioNow network
- Produced projects inside top tier advertising agencies
- Traveled Internationally (produced projects in France and London)
- Salesforce admin certified (currently inactive/expired)

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

## **Event Volunteer, PyTn 2020**

Assisted speakers with AV for their slides, and timed presentations

**Creative Production Volunteer, Cross Point Church** 

Served as booth and broadcast director, technical director, camera operator, and various roles as needed since 2006

# TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

## **Full-Stack Software Developer**

Nashville Software School | Nov 2019 - Present

Full-stack bootcamp focused on Python/Django, and front-end languages including JavaScript, React, SQL, CSS3, and HTML5

- Gained knowledge through teamwork and group projects
- Practiced Scrum Agile methodology, sprints, and daily stand-ups
- Technologies learned through bootcamp curriculum include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, JSON, JSON-server for API fetch/data storage, GitHub, Python, and SQL
- Remote learning from March 2020 to June 2020
- Workflow for projects included creation of Entity Relationship Diagrams through dbdiagram.com and sketchboard.me
- Mentored students as "little siblings" enrolled in the cohort six weeks behind in curriculum

# RECENT PROJECTS

#### mennanation.com

- Maintain website for Menna
- Lead promotion and music release efforts
- Spearhead video content creation initiatives

## Back-end capstone project (NSS): 'SONGWRYTR'

- Web application built with Python, Django, and SQL
- Designed for songwriters or managers manage writers, recordings, and publishing companies information.
- Models, Views, and Templates created in this Django Full-Stack Application to convert information in a SQL database and respond to HTTP requests with HTML output in web browser

## **EDUCATION**

## **Nashville Software School**

Web and Software Development Certificate

Nov 2019 - June 2020

Cohort with emphasis on Python, Django

### University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK

Bachelor of Business Administration, Marketing Aug 1999 - Aug 2003

Aug 1999 - Aug 2003

Involvement: Campus Activities Council (CAC) Public Relations Chair, CAC Film Series Chair, Vice-President Kappa Alpha Order, Honors Dorm Resident Advisor

Vancouver Film School, Vancouver, BC

Certification, Film Production

Aug 2003 - Aug 2004

Graduated with honours

# 臺灣大學 National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan Mandarin Chinese Level 1

Feb 2002 - May 2002

Graduated in 90th percentile, established foreign exchange between the University of Oklahoma and National Taiwan University